<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>blockchain on SongChain Blog</title><link>https://blog.songcha.in/tags/blockchain/</link><description>Recent content in blockchain on SongChain Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.songcha.in/tags/blockchain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Consensus Mechanisms</title><link>https://blog.songcha.in/p/consensus-mechanisms/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.songcha.in/p/consensus-mechanisms/</guid><description>In the traditional banking system, transactions are held on a central ledger at each bank. Banks have full control of this ledger and can modify it as they see fit. However, they are incentivized to ensure the accuracy of the ledger because their reputation is staked on it.
On a blockchain, the transaction ledger is decentralized and requires a consensus mechanism to ensure the transactions are accurately recorded. Three of the main consensus mechanisms include Proof of Work, Proof of Stake, and Proof of Authority.</description></item><item><title>A simplified view of Bitcoin and Blockchain’s inner workings</title><link>https://blog.songcha.in/p/a-simplified-view-of-bitcoin-and-blockchains-inner-workings/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.songcha.in/p/a-simplified-view-of-bitcoin-and-blockchains-inner-workings/</guid><description>Bitcoin’s blockchain is a database that records the flow of its native currency, bitcoin. Bitcoin’s blockchain is a distributed, cryptographic, and immutable database that uses proof-of-work to keep the ecosystem intact. Let’s do a brief overview of these terms to dive into the inner workings of Bitcoin’s blockchain.
Distributed refers to the way in which computers access Bitcoin’s blockchain. The great thing about Bitcoin’s blockchain is that it is decentralized, meaning any computer in the world can access it.</description></item></channel></rss>