<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on SongChain Blog</title><link>https://blog.songcha.in/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on SongChain Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.songcha.in/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A simplified view of Bitcoin and Blockchain’s inner workings</title><link>https://blog.songcha.in/p/a-simplified-view-of-bitcoin-and-blockchains-inner-workings/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.songcha.in/p/a-simplified-view-of-bitcoin-and-blockchains-inner-workings/</guid><description>Bitcoin’s blockchain is a database that records the flow of its native currency, bitcoin. Bitcoin’s blockchain is a distributed, cryptographic, and immutable database that uses proof-of-work to keep the ecosystem intact. Let’s do a brief overview of these terms to dive into the inner workings of Bitcoin’s blockchain.
Distributed refers to the way in which computers access Bitcoin’s blockchain. The great thing about Bitcoin’s blockchain is that it is decentralized, meaning any computer in the world can access it.</description></item><item><title>What is Cryptography?</title><link>https://blog.songcha.in/p/what-is-cryptography/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.songcha.in/p/what-is-cryptography/</guid><description>Cryptography is the science of secure information. It involves taking information and scrambling it in such a way that only the intended recipient can understand and use it.
Let’s think of cryptography in three categories: encryption on one side, decryption on the other, and cryptography stuck in the middle. Cryptography is the battlefield on which those trying to transmit information securely combat those attempting to decrypt and manipulate the information. Cryptography is not a new subject; humans have used cryptography for thousands of years.</description></item><item><title>Big Names in the NFT Space</title><link>https://blog.songcha.in/p/big-names-in-the-nft-space/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.songcha.in/p/big-names-in-the-nft-space/</guid><description>Every asset market has recognizable, household names attached to them. In terms of the equities markets, you may think of Warren Buffet, Benjamin Graham, or even Elon Musk. You think of these people for their popularity, and also their notoriety within the game that is the stock market. The market for NFTs is still in its infancy, but we are already seeing major players emerge as marker creators and market movers.</description></item><item><title>Explaining demand for NFTs, a personal anecdote</title><link>https://blog.songcha.in/p/explaining-demand-for-nfts-a-personal-anecdote/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.songcha.in/p/explaining-demand-for-nfts-a-personal-anecdote/</guid><description>When my friend and now business teammate Nicky told me about the idea of an NFT as a way to sell digital art, I told him he was absolutely insane. Me being the archaic iPhone 6 owner that I am, the idea of crypto art was so foreign to me. I voiced my opinion to Nicky that these art tokens would have no demand; after all they are just pictures or GIFs sitting on my computer screen.</description></item><item><title>Update on Dempsey Startup Competition</title><link>https://blog.songcha.in/p/update-on-dempsey-startup-competition/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.songcha.in/p/update-on-dempsey-startup-competition/</guid><description>We are excited to announce that SongChain has advanced to the Investment Round of the Dempsey Startup Competition at the University of Washington! SongChain is one of 30 teams to make it to this round and will be competing in a live tradeshow style event held over Zoom. Our UW employees, Nicky, Kenyon, and Michael will represent the rest of the team in this contest. The three will deliver a 60-second pitch video and 1-page business summary to a panel of prominent Seattle area entrepreneurs.</description></item><item><title>WTF is an NFT?</title><link>https://blog.songcha.in/p/wtf-is-an-nft/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.songcha.in/p/wtf-is-an-nft/</guid><description>You might have heard of bitcoin and blockchain, but what the hell is an NFT?
NFT stands for &amp;ldquo;non-fungible token,&amp;quot; a digital item that is built with the same blockchain technology as Bitcoin, but works a little differently.
First off, what does non-fungible mean? A better way to explain this is to talk about what the word fungible means. Bitcoin is fungible. Just like a US dollar, one Bitcoin is worth the same as another single Bitcoin.</description></item></channel></rss>